Independent Labour Party (Great Britain) Pamphlets 5336
Kheel Center for Labor-Management Documentation & Archives
Independent Labour Party (Great Britain) Pamphlets
1893-1950
Kheel Center for Labor-Management Documentation & Archives
Independent Labour Party (Great Britain)
5336
0.5 cubic feet
0.5 linear ft.
Pamphlets, publications.
Publications of the Independent Labour Party of Great Britain
5621949
General
Contact Information:
Kheel Center for Labor-Management Documentation and Archives Martin P. Catherwood Library 227 Ives Hall Cornell University Ithaca, NY 14853 (607) 255-3183> kheel_center@cornell.edu http://www.ilr.cornell.edu/library/kheel-center
Compiled by:
R. Miles, November 15, 2013
EAD encoding:
Kheel Staff, March 30, 2015
Scope and Contents
This collection consists of publications of the Independent Labour Party of Great Britain.
Conditions Governing Access
Access to the collections in the Kheel Center is restricted. Please contact a reference archivist for access to these materials.
Independent Labour Party (Great Britain)
5621949
- General conference reports, 1893-1902 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Item 1: Report of the First General Conference, 1893 (Box 1, Folder 1)
    Scope and Contents
    Author: Independent Labour Party (ILP)
    Format: Publication
    Language: English.
  - Item 2: Minutes of the Second Annual Conference, 1894 (Box 1, Folder 1)
    Notes: Held in the Lesser Free Trade Hall, Manchester. February 2-3, 1894.
  - Item 3: Report of the Third Annual Conference, 1895 (Box 1, Folder 1)
    Notes: Held at Newcastle, April 15-17, 1895
  - Item 4: Report of the Fourth Annual Conference, 1896 (Box 1, Folder 1)
    Notes: Held in the Mechanics' Hall, Nottingham, April 6-7, 1896
  - Item 5: Report of the Six Annual Conference, 1898 (Box 1, Folder 1)
    Notes: Held in the Priory Rooms, Birmingham, April 11-12, 1898
  - Item 6: Report of the Seventh Annual Conference, 1899 (Box 1, Folder 1)
    Notes: Held in the Albert Hall, Leeds, April 3-4, 1899
  - Item 7: Report of the Eighth Annual Conference, 1900 (Box 1, Folder 1)
    Notes: Held in the Waterloo Rooms, Glasgow, April 6-7, 1900
  - Item 8: Report of the Nineth Annual Conference, 1901 (Box 1, Folder 1)
    Notes: Held in the Cook Memorial Hall, Leicester, April 8-9, 1901
  - Item 9: Report of the Tenth Annual Conference, 1902 (Box 1, Folder 1)
    Notes: Held in the City Hall, Liverpool, March 31- April 1, 1902
- Publication lists (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Item 1: Catalogue of Socialist and Labour Books and Pamphlets (Box 1, Folder 2)
    Author: Publication Department
  - Item 2: Socialist and Labour Literature (Box 1, Folder 2)
- Constitution, 1932 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Item 1: Constitution and Rules of the I.L.P., 1932 (Box 1, Folder 3)
    Notes: As adopted at the Bradford Conference, July, 1932
- Pamphlets, 1920 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Item 1: The I.L.P. and the 3rd International, 1920 (Box 1, Folder 4)
- Pamphlets, 1924 (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Item 1: The Story of the I.L.P. and What It Stands For., 1924 (Box 1, Folder 5)
    Author: J. Ramsay MacDonald
- Pamphlets, 1925 (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - Item 1: Finance Enquiry Committee Reports, 1925 (Box 1, Folder 6)
    Author: ILP Finance Committee
  - Item 2: Industrial Policy for Socialists, 1925 (Box 1, Folder 6)
    Author: G. D. H. Cole
    Notes: I.L.P. Study Courses, No.11
  - Item 3: Social Insurance and the Worker, 1925 (Box 1, Folder 6)
    Author: Joseph L. Cohen
  - Item 4: Socialism for To-Day, 1925 (Box 1, Folder 6)
    Author: Henry Noel Brailsford
  - Item 5: The Capitalist Influence in Parliament, 1925 (Box 1, Folder 6)
    Author: A Back Bench Labour M.P.
    Notes: Reprint from The Socialist Review
- Pamphlets, 1926 (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - Item 1: India To-Day, 1926 (Box 1, Folder 7)
    Notes: A Report on Conditions in India and an Outline of Policy by the I.L.P. Indian Advisory Committee
  - Item 2: Labour's Road to Power: The Policy of the Living Income, 1926 (Box 1, Folder 7)
    Notes: Reprinted from The New Leader
  - Item 3: Socialism and Empire, 1926 (Box 1, Folder 7)
    Author: ILP Empire Policy Committee
    Notes: Report of the ILP Empire Policy Committee submitted to the Annual Conference of the Party
  - Item 4: The Living Wage, 1926 (Box 1, Folder 7)
    Author: Henry Noel Brailsford; John A. Hobson; A. Creech Jones; E. F. Wise
    Notes: A Report submitted to the National Administrative Council of the Independent Labour Party
  - Item 5: The Organized Worker: Problems of Trade Union Structure and Policy, 1926 (Box 1, Folder 7)
    Author: ILP Industrial Policy Committee
  - Item 6: Trade Unions and Socialism, 1926 (Box 1, Folder 7)
    Notes: A Report to the I.L.P. Conference, 1926, on the Industrial Aspect of Socialism
- Pamphlets, 1928 (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - Item 1: Socialism With Speed: An Outline of the ILP "Socialism In Our Time" Proposals, 1928 (Box 1, Folder 8)
    Author: A. Fenner Brockway; James Maxton
  - Item 2: The Capitalist Press: Who Owns It and Why, 1928 (Box 1, Folder 8)
    Author: Norman Angell
  - Item 3: Wages and Families: Why Trade Unionists Should Support Children's Allowances, 1928 (Box 1, Folder 8)
    Author: Ernest E. Hunter
  - Item 4: What the Surtax Is: Straight Answers to Some Plain Questions About the Surtax., 1928 (Box 1, Folder 8)
    Author: H. B. Lees- Smith
- Pamphlets, 1929 (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - Item 1: Wages and Families: Why Workers Should Support Children's Allowances, 1929 (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - Item 2: Wealth, Work, and Wages, 1929 (Box 1, Folder 9)
    Author: John Paton
  - Item 3: Wheat Dumping v. State Purchase, 1929 (Box 1, Folder 9)
    Author: E. F. Wise
    Notes: Parliamentary Series, no.1
  - Item 4: J. Maxton, M.P. on the Government's Unemployment Proposals, 1929 (Box 1, Folder 9)
    Author: James Maxton
    Notes: Parliamentary Series, no.2. Speech in the House of Commons, November 4, 1929.
  - Item 5: Labour In Office, 1929 (Box 1, Folder 9)
    Author: Francis Johnson
    Notes: Complete List of The Ministry Labour Members of the Parliament and Labour Candidates
  - Item 6: Labour In Office, 1929 (Box 1, Folder 9)
    Notes: Complete List of The Ministry Labour Members of the Parliament and Labour Candidates. Copy 2.
  - Item 7: Re-Organize Industry, 1929 (Box 1, Folder 9)
    Author: Balfour Committee
    Notes: A constructive plan for the Transition from Capitalism to Socialism
  - Item 8: Sir Oswald Mosley, M.P. Replies to Mr. Baldwin on Industrial Problems and the Socialists., 1929 (Box 1, Folder 9)
    Author: Oswald Mosley
    Notes: Reprinted from the Daily Express
  - Item 9: Socialism for Beginners, 1929 (Box 1, Folder 9)
    Author: Katharine Bruse Glasier
    Notes: Dedicated to the Memory of Glen at seven years old.
  - Item 10: The Roads to Socialism, 1929 (Box 1, Folder 9)
    Notes: Chairman's Address at the ILP Conference
  - Item 11: The Tories and the Russian Trade, 1929 (Box 1, Folder 9)
    Author: W. P. Coates; E. F. Wise
    Notes: How the Policy of the Conservative Government has Hampered British Trade with Russia
- Pamphlets, 1931 (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - Item 1: A Socialist Plan for Unemployment, 1931 (Box 1, Folder 10)
    Author: A. Fenner Brockway
    Notes: Speeh on the Conservative Motion of Censure, April 16, 1931
  - Item 2: Heaven for Twopence and Other Sketches, 1931 (Box 1, Folder 10)
    Author: Minnie Pallister
  - Item 3: The "Anomalies" Bill: Why its Rejection was Moved., 1931 (Box 1, Folder 10)
    Author: George Buchanan; James Maxton; A. Fenner Brockway
    Notes: Together with a Report of the All Night Sitting and the Final Fight.
  - Item 4: The "City" or the Nation?, 1931 (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - Item 5: The I.L.P. and the Crisis, 1931 (Box 1, Folder 10)
- Pamphlets, 1932 (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - Item 1: Insurance and the Money Trust: How the Insured are Fleeced, 1932 (Box 1, Folder 11)
    Author: W. Tait
  - Item 2: Money and Credit: A Little Talk on Finance, 1932 (Box 1, Folder 11)
    Author: T. Stairs
  - Item 3: The I.L.P. Says No to the Present Standing Orders of the Labour Party, 1932 (Box 1, Folder 11)
    Author: F. W. Jowett
  - Item 4: The Jugglers of Finance are Bleeding the Nation White, 1932 (Box 1, Folder 11)
    Author: Fred Tait
  - Item 5: The Policy of the I.L.P., 1932 (Box 1, Folder 11)
- Pamphlets, 1933 (Box 1, Folder 12)
  - Item 1: A Six Hour Working Day, 1933 (Box 1, Folder 12)
    Author: R. C. Wallhead; James Maxton
- Pamphlets (Box 1, Folder 13)
  no dates
  - Item 1: A World of Justice and Love: Its Possibility (Box 1, Folder 13)
    Author: Archie McArthur
    Notes: no.3
  - Item 2: All About the I.L.P. (Box 1, Folder 13)
  - Item 3: Banks, Prices and Unemployment (Box 1, Folder 13)
    Author: John MacLeod
  - Item 4: Nationalise the Railways (Box 1, Folder 13)
    Author: F. E. Lawley
  - Item 5: Real Facts About the Cotton Trade (Box 1, Folder 13)
    Author: Tom Myers
    Notes: Employees and Wages; Production, Exports, Imports; Foreign Competition; Profits and Capitalism
  - Item 6: Saving and Spending: Why Production is Clogged (Box 1, Folder 13)
    Author: John A. Hobson
    Notes: "New Leader" Reprints, no.2
  - Item 7: Socialise the National Income! (Box 1, Folder 13)
    Author: John Wheatley
  - Item 8: Socialism and Capitalism (Box 1, Folder 13)
    Author: George Benson
  - Item 9: Socialism for Women: Not Only the "Intelligent" Women, but All Women (Box 1, Folder 13)
  - Item 10: The Crime of Empire (Box 1, Folder 13)
    Author: C. A. Smith
  - Item 11: The Making of an Agitator, or the Early Days of Keir Hardie (Box 1, Folder 13)
    Author: William Stewart
    Notes: Chapter one of "J. Keir Hardie: A Biography"
  - Item 12: The Reform of Parliament (Box 1, Folder 13)
    Notes: Reports submitted to the Annual Conference of the I.L.P.
  - Item 13: Twenty Points for Socialism (Box 1, Folder 13)
  - Item 14: Unemployment: Its Cause and Cure (Box 1, Folder 13)
    Author: Thomas Dickson
    Notes: Mrs. Mary Citizen, John Citizen, and Mr. Commonsense discuss the problem
  - Item 15: What the I.L.P. Youth Guild Stands For! (Box 1, Folder 13)
    Author: John Nixon
  - Item 16: What the I.L.P. Youth Guild Stands For! (Box 1, Folder 13)
    Notes: Copy 2.
  - Item 17: Will Capital Leave the Country? (Box 1, Folder 13)
    Author: Hugh Dalton